Isn't the history of
computers supper interesting.
I love going back in
time and seeing how
we got to this exciting
point in computing.
You've already taken
the first few steps to
building your foundational
knowledge of IT.
Before we dive deeper,
I'll just take a moment
to introduce myself.
My name is Devan Sri-Tharan.
I've been working
in IT for 10 years.
I'm a Corporate Operations
Engineer at Google,
where I get to tackle challenging
and complex IT issues.
Thinking back, my
first experience with
tech began when I was
about nine years old.
My dad brought home the
families first computer.
I remember my dad holding
a floppy disk and telling me
that there was a game on it.
To my dad's amazement, I
somehow managed to copy
the game from disk onto
the computer's hard drive.
While it might seem like
a trivial task now,
this device was just so
new to us back then.
Sure, I loved the different
games I could play
but what I really loved
tinkering with the machine,
trying to get it to do
what I want it to do.
While that floppy disk in
computer might have ignited
my passion for technology,
was actually my first
few job experiences
that really started to
shape my IT career.
One was in retail
selling baby furniture
and the other was at a
postal store where I helped
customers chip their packages
and became the
one-person IT crew.
It might sound all that
working in retail
inspired my career,
but I've realized I've really
enjoyed communicating
with customers,
trying to understand their
needs and offering a solution.
My first experience working
directly in IT was in
college as an IT support
specialist intern.
From there, I worked
as an IT consultant
to decommission an
entire IT environment.
This was my first
experience working
directly with large
IT infrastructure
and pushing myself outside
my comfort level as
a college student.
I bring up these few
jobs for a reason.
These experiences helped
shape my career in IT.
I knew at that time that
I wanted to go into tech,
but I struggled where I
want it to focus my career.
Starting at Google as an
IT journalists allowed
me to experience many
different areas of technology.
It allowed me to figure out
the jobs I didn't want to
do before I was able to identify
exactly what I did want to do.
Really passionate about
IT infrastructure,
but you can't understand
infrastructure until you
understand hardware.
Let's dig in, in IT,
hardware is an essential
topic to understand.
You might find yourself
replacing faulty components
or even upgrading an entire
fleet of machines one day.
By the end of this lesson,
you'll be able to describe
all the physical parts
of computer and how
they work together.
You'll even be able to
build your own computer.
Once you figured out
how one computer works,
you'll be able to understand how
any type of computer works.
Excited, I am.
Let's get started.